tonight I'm here to talk to you about
none of the above you know how it is
around election time and you decide not
to vote because the two candidates are
so repulsive I never wear a suit I mean
these are just things that politicians
use to trick you into thinking that
they're respectable well the politician
that was a clip from a movie Brewster's
Millions and I'm using it just as a fun
way to introduce an idea that idea being
none of the above and by that
specifically what I mean is that a
campaign be started to encourage people
next time they go to the polls to
instead of voting for any of the options
that are on there to draw an additional
option none of the above put a little
box next to it tick the little box and
stick that in the ballot box and I mean
it's not merely as a protest but there's
very much more to it than that and I'm
gonna make the short series of videos
probably four of them in total to unpack
this in full so this is the introductory
one and for this one I really just want
to put the idea out there and very
briefly touch on some of the things I'm
going to explore in more detail in the
future videos and so the overarching
point of none of the above is to create
a space in which an inclusive
wide-ranging free discussion can occur
in which new methodologies new
philosophies new principles for
organizing ourselves can be looked at
and can be tried out on small scales and
experiments can be grabbed and so on and
so on and so on
because within the current framework of
unbelievably limited political debate if
you can even call it there there is no
possibility of meaningful and
constructive solutions to the problems
that faces emerging so that's the
overarching point and then within that
there are I guess three sub themes the
first of those is fraction astuteness
and disunity I mean we see it everywhere
we look I'm personally part of the
resource-based economics movement you
know part of the activist community and
you know even within there people who
were all on the same team
find little things to argue about
primarily I think out of a sense of
frustration but the point is that the
simplicity of none of the above we
wouldn't conflict with anything that
anyone else is doing you know other
activists other changemakers whatever it
is they are personally interested in
seeking to change none of the above can
run alongside that the second part of it
would be a recognition that our systems
are incapable of coming up to coming up
with solutions to problems which they
themselves have caused and again I'll go
into this more but again it comes back
to clearing a space if the current
structures institutions thought
processes are incapable of solving the
problems then we need to clear them out
of the way in order to make room for the
kinds of thought processes and
procedures and so on that have some
chance of solving the problems and the
third part of it is about reclaiming
sovereignty reclaiming our power as the
electorate as the people as individuals
as well and so what a widespread none of
the above campaign could potentially
achieve if you know if 51% of people
vote none of the above this effectively
withdraws the consent of the people for
the government to govern them right and
it's once again an acknowledgment that
we need a space to come up with things
which are different to come up with
things which are better to come up with
things that nobody has yet thought of
but have no chance of thinking over at
least the ideas have no chance of
gaining any traction
within the current framework so it's
it's a recognition of all of those
things at once so I guess that's really
all I have to say for now I'm just going
to leave you with a clip from a speech
that JFK gave some fifty five years ago
which i think is apropos and thank you
for listening our problems are man-made
therefore they can be solved by man and
man can be as big as he wants no problem
of human destiny is beyond human beings
man's reason and spirit have often
solved the seemingly unsolvable
and we believe they can do it again for
in the final analysis our most basic
common link is that we all inhabit this
small planet we all breathe the same air
we all cherish our children's futures
and we are all mortal
the only thing that silly is the power
of the people's vote and I think the
people should use it to vote for
[Applause]